（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）
桐仁(きりひと)のヤツ 粋なことを…
Kirihito's being clever again.
Here...
ここは―
Shibakiyama
Stable
They produce top-ranked pros.
It's renowned for its intense practices.
角界でも１〜２を争う
猛稽古で知られる―
The Shibakiyama Stable!
柴木山(しばきやま)部屋
They're part of the pro sumo world,
which I want to conquer!
（火ノ丸）
ワシが目指す大相撲の一端
I'll gladly take their help!
胸 貸してもらいます！
Bout 6
"Charge!! Shibakiyama Stable"
Out! Keep things moving!
（力士）
おら　すぐ出ろ すぐ！
（力士）エイッ！
It's so intense...
（咲(さき)）すごい熱気やな
Now! Push, push!
（柴木山）
そこだ　押せ押せ！
Master Shibakiyama is still as sharp-eyed
and intimidating as he was when he competed.
（咲）柴木山親方
鋭い眼光と威圧感は
現役当時と変わってない
Oh, very nice! Good strike!
（柴木山）
うん いいよ　いい当たり
Just keep your chin a bit lower!
もう少し顎を引くと
もっといいよ
He's nicer than I expected.
（咲）意外と優しいんやね
Saki-chan, thank you for
coming all the way to watch us.
咲ちゃん　遠くから見学に
来てくれて ありがとうね
Th-The pleasure's all mine.
I'm looking forward to the next two days.
（咲）あっ はい
今日と 明日の２日間
よろしくお願いします
He's awfully upbeat today.
（力士）なんか今日は
やけに気合い入ってますね
M-Maybe it's because there's
a high school girl in here.
じょ…女子高生が
見学に来てるから？
（力士）ハハッ…
それも大いにあるが―
That's part of it,
今日は もう１人
１日体験入門に来るんだよ
but another student's also
having a trial with us today.
Some high school hotshot, apparently.
超高校級の大物選手がな
A high school hotshot?
超高校級？
ンン〜ッ…　早く来ないかな
When will he get here?
I can vouch for his skill.
（桐仁）実力は保証します
He will one day be the top-ranked
pro sumo wrestler. You can count on it.
いずれ 角界を背負う男です
期待していいですよ
（柴木山）未来の関取候補
絶対 ウチに入門させる
A future sekitori...
I want him for my stable!
Master, he's coming this way!
（寺原(てらはら)）
親方　お見えになりましたよ
おっ…　来たか
He's here!
Sorry I'm late!
遅くなって すみません
少し道に迷ってしまって
I got lost on the way.
Thank you for letting me train here today!
今日は１日
よろしくお願いします
うんうん 君は付き添いだね
例のほら　潮(うしお)君はどこかね？
You must be his assistant, right?
Come, now. Where's Ushio-kun?
Huh? Well... I'm Ushio Hinomaru
of the Odachi High School sumo club.
（火ノ丸）えっ いや
ワシが大太刀(おおだち)高校相撲部の
潮火ノ丸です
潮火ノ丸…
"Ushio Hinomaru"?
Th-This can't be right!
（柴木山）は… 話が違う！
（火ノ丸）えっ？
I m-mean... how tall are you?
だ… だって君
その… 身長は？
Oh, 152 cm, sir.
あっ はい　152センチです
O-Only 152 cm?!
ひゃ… 152！？　そっか…
I see...
Master's looking mighty glum all of a sudden.
（力士）親方ってば
肩落としちゃって
Can you blame him?
ムリもないよ
But the kid's here now.
（力士）
しかし来ちゃったもんは
しょうがねえ
Let's just humor him for today.
今日のところは
彼に合わせてやりますか
（寺原）ほほほお〜
いいすり足だね
You've got great footwork.
Ushio-kun, was it?
潮君だっけ？　俺は寺原
I'm Terahara.
I was a high school sumo
myself until recently.
俺も この間まで
高校相撲の選手だったんだ
As your predecessor,
I'll practice with you today.
今日は 先輩として
胸貸してやる
Don't hold back, you hear?
（寺原）遠慮はするなよ
（火ノ丸）はい！
Yes, sir!
I'm still feeling a little stiff.
まだ少し体が硬いな
緊張しとるんか？
Am I nervous?
Is it my imagination, or has the mood
lightened since Ushio-kun showed up?
気のせいか 潮君が来てから
少し空気が緩んだ？
Jeez, I know we're just sparring,
but these guys sure are taking it easy.
…たく　全力で
やっちゃいけねえってのも―
なかなかダルいッスね
It's all for the spectators, man.
接待稽古ってやつだよ
Well, he's a fan of sumo, so we might as
well let him enjoy himself until he leaves.
まあ　せっかく
相撲が好きで来たんだし―
楽しい気分で
帰ってもらおうや
You should be warmed up by now, yeah?
（力士）
そろそろ 体 温まったろう？
Let's step into the ring.
（力士）土俵に入りな
（火ノ丸）はい
Yes, sir!
（力士）おっと…
その前に ちょっとした―
Oh, before all that, wanna do something fun?
レクリエーションが
あるんだけどやってみるかい
Jonidan Inoseyama
Tumbler
Shimasakio
T-shirt
Jonokuchi Uda
Towel
Master Shibakiyama
'ster's ? ?
Makushita Kawataumi
Invitation to
the next tournament
Hirayama
Great fights DVD (signed)
Sandanme Chibato
Next year's calendar
(signed)
Shinodomaru
Sumo jinku folk CD
Kunpu
Pair of teacups
Knock them over and win!!
Shibakiyama Stable Goods
Every kid who comes to
practice with us gets a shot.
（力士）体験入門に
来てくれた子には―
漏れなく
挑戦権が与えられる
Master Shibakiyama
'ster's ? ?
Makushita Kawataumi
Invitation to
the next tournament
Hirayama
Great fights DVD (signed)
Sandanme Chibato
Next year's calendar
(signed)
Shinodomaru
Sumo jinku folk CD
Kunpu
Pair of teacups
Knock them over and win!!
Shibakiyama Stable Goods
It's the "Shibakiyama
Knock 'em Out Challenge"!
その名も 〝柴木山
押し出しチャレンジ〞！
ぶつかり稽古の要領で
土俵の外まで押し出すと―
If you push one of us out of the ring, look!
なんと部屋特製グッズを
プレゼントだ！
Shibakiyama Stable
You'll win special stable merchandise!
へえ…
Okay, you're up first, Terahara!
（力士）
よし  じゃ最初は寺原
Right!
（寺原）はいよ！
（力士）
ハハッ…　すごい体格差だな
There's a humongous size difference.
Good luck, Ushio-kun!
（力士）頑張れよ 潮君
まあ 最後は
勝たせてやるんだけどな
Ah, I'll let you win in the end...
I'll step out of the ring after
you've struggled for a bit.
ちょっと苦戦してから
土俵を割るか
Tera-chan.
（柴木山）寺ちゃん
（寺原）えっ？
（柴木山）こりゃ
本気でやったほうがいい
You should probably take this seriously.
ンッ…　は… はい
Yes, sir.
Here I come.
いきます　ンッ！
グオ〜ッ！
（寺原）ンンッ…
（力士）ウソだろう？
No way...
（寺原）ングッ！
Even though I'd love some
Shibakiyama Stable merch,
（火ノ丸）柴木山部屋グッズ
めっちゃ欲しいんスけどね
my team needs me to bring
back more than just souvenirs.
手土産が それだけじゃ
仲間に合わす顔がないんスよ
Please let me experience
a full-blown Shibakiyama session!
ください ワシに
柴木山部屋の本気の稽古！
Ishigami
High
School
Sumo
Club
（蛍(けい)）
今ごろ 火ノ丸さんは―
Hinomaru-san must be practicing
with the pros right about now.
大相撲力士と
稽古してるんですよね
Isn't that amazing?
すごいな
At the Shibakiyama Stable, was it?
（佑真(ゆうま)）
柴木山部屋っつったっけ？
Yeah.
（小関(おぜき)）うん
Say, why did you choose
the Shibakiyama Stable?
ねえ
なんで柴木山部屋なの？
Even among the pros, they're known
as a training-heavy stable.
角界でも屈指の稽古量の多さ
Before he retired from the sport, the
master was famous for his love of training.
あそこの親方は現役の頃から
稽古の虫で有名でしたからね
He wasn't blessed with a godlike physique.
決して恵まれた体格では
ありませんでしたが―
His fearsome attacks, booming and relentless,
earned him the moniker of "Firecracker."
その苛烈で うるさい攻めは
“爆竹”の異名で恐れられ―
He even gave yokozuna Yamatokuni
a great deal of trouble in his prime.
全盛期の横綱  大和国(やまとくに)をも
苦しめるほどでした
Kunzan
Even with his small stature,
he preferred to fight head-on.
小兵ながら
真っ向勝負にこだわり―
Yamatokuni
生涯 一度も―
Throughout his career,
he never changed how he charged.
立ち合い変化をしなかった
Does that sound like someone you know?
なんだか 誰かさんに
似てると思いませんか？
Yamatokuni
I want to know what the master thinks
when he sees how Hinomaru fights.
（桐仁）火ノ丸の相撲を見て
親方は どう思うのか
そして もうひとつは
柴木山部屋の あの力士…
And then, there's this other sumo
at the Shibakiyama Stable...
This stable's known for intense training,
but I used to do far more in my prime.
（柴木山）
ウチは猛稽古といわれるが―
僕の現役の頃に比べれば
軽いもんだ
Even so, plenty complained
about the regimen and left.
それでも 多くの者が
音を上げて 去っていった
I thought you were like those other boys
who didn't have the commitment.
君も その手の―
覚悟なき相撲少年のひとりと
タカをくくっていた
I must apologize for my rudeness,
Ushio Hinomaru.
（柴木山）君を侮った
その非礼をわびねばなるまい
潮火ノ丸
The pro league won't accept
someone of your height,
大相撲が拒む その上背で―
but Sandanme-division wrestlers
can't even come close to beating you.
３段目クラスが
まるで歯が立たんとは…
He's too much for you guys.
お前らには荷が重い
下がってな
Stand back.
You sometimes show cracks
when you grab a mawashi belt.
（柴木山）時折廻(まわ)しを取ると
もろさを見せるが―
何かを ねらってのことか？
Is that a setup for something?
No, more importantly,
and most importantly of all...
いや それより何より…
One more time!
もういっちょう！
What is that gleam in your eyes?
（柴木山）
そのギラついた目は何だ？
Okay, you're on!
お〜し　来い！
His enthusiasm is spreading
to the other sumo wrestlers.
（柴木山）彼の士気の高さに
弟子たちも感化され―
熱を帯びていく
This mood is similar to when...
この雰囲気は まるで…
Who is that over there?
（冴ノ山(さえのやま)）彼は何者ですか？
Ushio Hinomaru-kun.
潮火ノ丸君です
体験入門に来たそうです
He's here for a one-day trial.
（冴ノ山）
あ〜 そういえば…
やりますね 彼
Oh, I heard he was coming.
He is rather good.
（柴木山）おい 紀(のり)ちゃん
Hey, Nori-chan!
Stop the peeping tom act.
何をコソコソしとるんだ
早く入ってこい
Get in here already.
My apologies.
（冴ノ山）これは失礼
It sounded like you were having
such a good session,
あまりに稽古場の雰囲気が
良かったものですから―
I did not wish to interrupt.
それを
壊してしまうのではと…
Actually, to tell you the truth,
I could not look away.
（冴ノ山）いや
見ほれていたと
言うほうが正確でしょうか？
あっ…
西前頭(にしまえがしら)九枚目 冴ノ山！
The ninth-ranked west
maegashira, Saenoyama!
Good morning, sekitori!
（力士たち）
おはようございます 関取！
So far, Ushio-kun's been fighting trainees
from the makushita division and below.
潮君が今まで
相手にしてたのは―
幕下以下の力士養成員
It might sound rude, but they're
second-rate pros, maybe even third-rate.
失礼を承知で言うと
彼らはプロの中でも２軍３軍
Makuuchi
Juryo
Makushita
Sandanme
Of the 700 or more pro sumo wrestlers,
７００人を超える
力士たちの中でも―
Jonidan
Makuuchi
Juryo
Makushita
Sandanme
only the 70 in the juryo division
and above are allowed
大銀杏(おおいちょう)を結い
関取と呼ばれるのは―
Jonokuchi
to tie their hair in an oicho topknot
and call themselves sekitori.
十両 幕内を合わせた
僅か70人のみ
Maezumo
And only sekitori are allowed to wear
a white mawashi belt during practice.
その関取のみに許される
白い稽古廻し
He's a first-rate pro, Ushio-kun.
ついに１軍の登場やで 潮君
Ushio-kun has created a mood similar
to a practice session for the sekitori.
（柴木山）
潮君が作った雰囲気は―
関取がいる稽古場を
彷彿(ほうふつ)とさせた
But now that an actual sekitori is here,
will things get even tenser?
…が 実際 関取が来ると
やはり もう１段 締まるか
Good morning.
Thank you for your assistance earlier.
（冴ノ山）
おはようございます
先ほどは どうも
No, thank you for letting me be here.
（咲）こちらこそ
おジャマしてます
Good morning, master.
（冴ノ山）
おはようございます 親方
（柴木山）うむ…
関取　ワシと一番
お願いします！
Sekitori! Please have a bout with me!
潮君 関取はまだ
到着したばかりで…
Uh, Ushio-kun, the sekitori
only just got here...
I would like to duel you as well.
（冴ノ山）こちらこそ
よろしくお願いします
Huh? Sekitori?
（力士）えっ？　関取？
I may not look it,
but I happen to be a real curious cat.
こう見えて 私
好奇心旺盛なんです
Is this the opportunity you
were hoping for, Kirihito?
（火ノ丸）これが
お前の望む展開か？　桐仁よ
Even the weaker fighters
were very adept, but...
さすがに下位とてレベルは
高かった  じゃが しかし…
Kusanagi was much stronger!
草薙(くさなぎ)は
こんなもんじゃなかった
Ordinary opponents won't be enough.
そこそこじゃいかんのです
I need to fight wrestlers
on a whole other level!
もっと格上と
やらんといかんのですよ
Saenoyama-zeki!
冴ノ山関！
I'll admit, we looked down
on you when you first walked in.
（柴木山）確かに我々は
君のことを見くびった
But...
だが…
はっきよい！
Spirit!
Why isn't he moving?
なぜ動かん？
...don't look down on the pros, boy!
（柴木山）
プロを侮るな 小僧
This is it!
（火ノ丸）それでこそ…
も… もういっちょう
お願いします
O-One more time, please!
This is what I came for!
来た甲斐(かい)がある！
まるで手応えがねえ
I feel like I'm doing nothing to him.
His lower body is so flexible,
my strikes don't affect him.
下半身が柔らかいんか？
力が受け流される
But in a flash, his body becomes rock hard!
瞬間  すさまじい硬さも
見せる
This is the power of the pro!
これがプロ！？
"Be like water."
“水のごとし”
親方の教えです
That is the lesson our master taught me.
Your form must be fluid, but you
must also strike with torrential force.
その形を自在に変えながら
時に激しく打つ
Like water, huh?
水のごとし…
Your sumo is like fire, forever raging.
（冴ノ山）君の相撲は
炎のように燃え盛るばかり
You could say it's heroic,
but you might also call it sloppy.
よく言えば 豪快ですが
悪く言えば 雑です
Thank you very much.
（冴ノ山）ありがとうございました
（火ノ丸）えっ？
I understand your abilities now.
（冴ノ山）君の実力は分かりました
（火ノ丸）待っとくれ 関取！
Please wait, sekitori!
Any further bouts would be a waste of time.
これ以上続けても
時間のムダです
It's my duty to achieve the rank of yokozuna,
a glory my master was unable to taste.
私には
親方の果たせなかった夢―
横綱になるという
託された責務がありますので
I'm only here today!
（火ノ丸）
今日１日だけなんです
Please, just one more bout!
せめて あと一番！
The one thing I still do not understand
is what spurs you on.
（冴ノ山）何が君を
そこまで駆り立てるのか―
それだけが分かりません
Have you not had enough?
もう十分でしょう？
Even if you cannot best me,
there is no shame in it.
私に勝てなくともムキに
なる必要はありませんよ
You certainly cannot be called weak.
君は決して弱くない
You will be moderately
successful in high school sumo.
高校相撲ならそれなりに
結果も出せるでしょう
"Moderately successful" isn't good enough.
それなりじゃいかんのですよ
I will become a yokozuna,
just like you intend to!
ワシも 関取と同じ
大相撲の横綱になるんです！
Isn't that reason enough?
理由なら
これで十分でしょう！
Like me?
（冴ノ山）同じ？
憧れで語る君の“横綱”と―
Your dream of becoming a yokozuna
is borne from childish idealism.
身をもって その高みを知り
なお口にする私の“横綱”が
Meanwhile, I speak of it knowing full well
how long and arduous a road it is.
What makes you think
we are one and the same?
どうして同じだと思う？
You asked for one more bout.
あと一番と言いましたね？
いいでしょう
Very well.
Maybe you believe you will
grow taller, or perhaps...
これから身長が伸びると
信じているのか それとも…
Regardless, those words that
passed your lips so frivolously
どちらにせよ 君が
軽々しく吐いたその言葉は―
全力士への侮辱だ
are an insult to all sumo wrestlers.
The sekitori looks serious.
（力士）
関取…　本気の顔だ
Don't back down.
This is exactly why I'm here!
ひるむなよ
ワシは何しに来た？
This is my last chance
to find a way to evolve.
進化のきっかけをつかむ
最後のチャンスじゃ！
I need to do something about my charge.
まずは立ち合いを
どうにかせんといかん
I don't have the skill
to overpower a sekitori.
今のワシには
関取を上回る技術はない
All I can do is go as low
and as fast as I can.
ワシにできるのは…
ひたすらに低く 速く…
A spider stance?
平蜘蛛(ひらぐも)…
That's it. Keep experimenting.
そうだ　いろいろ試すといい
Spirit!
はっきよい！
（火ノ丸）ウッ！
（寺原）張り手！
A slap!
Side slaps are banned
in amateur competitions!
横から張るのは
アマチュアでは禁じ手だ！
This feeling...
手応えが…膝のクッションで
衝撃を吸収した？
He used his knees as a cushion
to absorb the impact.
After dozens of bouts,
I don't have much strength left.
（火ノ丸）
何十番もこなしたせいで
うまく力が入らん
"Be like water."
水のごとし…
That fluidity varies your rhythm and
dictates the tempo in a sumo bout!
この脱力が
相撲に緩急を生むわけか
燃え盛るだけが炎じゃない
Fire doesn't just rage, huh?
It flickers and burns!
揺らめき 焦がせ！
So what you've been
waiting for all day is...
（柴木山）まさか 君が今日
ずっと ねらっていたのは…
Kirihito found me an extremely
skilled sparring partner.
（火ノ丸）
桐仁がワシに用意してくれた
極上の稽古相手
I need to make the most of today!
今日という日をモノにしろ！
ワシは行くぞ
あんたをのみ込んで頂点(てっぺん)へ！
Here I come. I'll swallow you
and reach the top!
（冴ノ山）来る！下から何か
とてつもないものが！
Some incredible force is
erupting from deep inside him!
（咲）潮君が
つぶれるのが先やったけど―
The sekitori pushed
Ushio-kun to the ground first,
but his knee still went down!
ついに関取が膝をついた！
My body was moving on its own.
体が勝手に動いた
It wasn't the same as what
Kirihito did, but it felt so natural.
桐仁が見せた形とは違ったが
妙に しっくりと来た
This must be a new technique unique to me.
これがきっとワシだけの新技
しかし あと１歩の
ところで…
But I was so close...
Damn! Dammit!
くそ！　くそ！
（冴ノ山）これが
最後という約束でしたね
As agreed, that bout was our last.
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました
I will expect to see you
here again tomorrow.
（冴ノ山）
また 明日 ここに来なさい
もう少し君のことを
見てみたいと思いました
I would like to see
a little more of what you can do.
I may not look it,
but I happen to be a real curious cat.
こう見えて
好奇心旺盛なんですよ
あっ…
よろしくお願いします！
I'll be here!
（桐仁）
…で どうだったんです？
補習は
So how was your remedial class?
（千比路(ちひろ)）それより石神(いしがみ)の
ゲンゴロウってヤツが来てよ
Forget that. Someone called
Gengoro from Ishigami showed up.
ゲンゴロウ？
Gengoro?
Hello.
はい…　ああ
えっ “泊まる”？
Yeah.
What? You're staying?
Saenoyama-zeki's sparring
with me tomorrow.
（火ノ丸）冴ノ山関に明日も
稽古つけてもらうことに
なってな
So the master said I might as well stay over.
なら泊まったほうが
いいだろうって―
親方が言ってくれて
Think you'll acquire that new technique?
つかめそうか？　新技
I'll let you know that when I see you.
（火ノ丸）
楽しみに待っとってくれ
じゃあな
Bye.
Was that Hinomaru-san?
（蛍）火ノ丸さんですか？
（桐仁）ああ
Yeah. He's staying at the Shibakiyama
Stable and training there again tomorrow.
今日は柴木山部屋に泊まって
明日も稽古
つけてもらうらしい
They must really like him.
（佑真）
気に入られたんだな あいつ
We have to work hard, too!
（小関）俺たちも頑張ろう
潮に負けないように
We can't leave it all up to him.
Yeah! I'll be working hard tomorrow!
（千比路）
おう！明日は俺も やるぜ！
No more failing tests, okay?
もう赤点
取らないでくださいね
Yeah, you can count on me!
おうとも　任せとけって！
（桐仁）いや そういう感じ
いいですから
Take it down a notch.
本物の相撲部屋の
ちゃんこ鍋じゃ！
Real sumo stable chankonabe stew!
Hey, Hinomaru-chan, good work today!
（柴木山）
おう 火ノ丸ちゃん
ご苦労さん
"H-Hinomaru-chan"?
（火ノ丸）
ひ… 火ノ丸ちゃん？
Come over and eat with us.
（柴木山）
こっち来て食べなさい
You sure it's okay?
The sekitori's still eating.
いいんスかね？まだ関取が…
Today's an exception. Go chow down.
（寺原）
今日は特別だ　ほら 行け
Y-Yes, sir!
（火ノ丸）あっ はい！
フフフッ…
ほんまやったら―
The apprentices usually eat last, don't they?
新弟子は
いちばん最後やもんね
Still...
しかし…
This doesn't feel right.
落ち着かんのぅ
I hear that you are a national
treasure, Onimaru Kunitsuna.
（冴ノ山）
君 国宝らしいですね　鬼丸国綱(おにまるくにつな)
A n-national treasure?
（寺原）こ… 国宝！？
It's not a big deal.
People just call me that.
あっ いや 周りが
言ってるだけで…
That's not true.
そんなことないやろう
I heard you held your own against Kusanagi.
草薙と互角に
戦ったっていうやない
Who told you that?
なんで そんなことまで？
I'm a sumo club manager, so I get
to hear a lot of high school sumo gossip.
私 相撲部の
マネージャーやから―
高校相撲のニュースには
ちょっと詳しいんよ
By Kusanagi, do you mean...
草薙とは もしかして…
Kuze Sosuke, the national
treasure, Kusanagi Sword.
久世草介(くぜそうすけ)　国宝 草薙剣(くさなぎのつるぎ)
The son of former yokozuna, Yamatokuni.
元横綱 大和国の息子です
Yamatokuni...
（力士）大和国…
（力士）国宝？
A national treasure?
He's somewhat of a hot topic these days.
今 ちょっとした
話題なんですよ
角界入りすれば
番付を駆け上がるってね
People say he will rise quickly through
the ranks if he turns professional.
I see. So you're in the same
generation as his son, huh?
なるほど
あいつの息子と同世代か
そいつは難儀だねえ
Tough break, kiddo.
Who was stronger, me or Junior?
（冴ノ山）私とジュニア
どっちが強かった？
そ… そりゃ
関取相手よりは―
W-Well, I did much better against him
than I did against you.
ワシもいいとこ
見せられましたよ
（笑い声）
（力士）そりゃそうだ
Of course you did!
Hey, your chopsticks aren't moving!
（寺原）ほ〜ら
箸が止まってるぞ
丼３杯はノルマだからな
This stew's a three-bowl minimum!
Y-Yes, sir!
（火ノ丸）は… はい！
After you've eaten your fill,
（寺原）
腹いっぱい食べたあとは―
it's time for a nap.
昼寝だ
（寺原の いびき）
We're off to buy groceries for dinner.
夕飯の食材 買いに行くぞ
（火ノ丸）下っ端になるほど
雑務も多く 忙しい
You have to do a lot of chores
when you're an apprentice.
Yes, sir!
But... it's a lot of fun.
でも 楽しい
I know it's not all fun and games.
You live to compete.
分かっとる　現実は楽しい
ばかりじゃない勝負の世界
They must all have private
doubts and anxieties.
みんな 見えない所で
苦悩を抱えとるはずじゃ
I know all that.
分かっとる
I made some food, too!
This is the world of pro sumo
I've been longing to join.
ずっと憧れていた
大相撲の世界
Whoa, I might ask you to marry me!
It's like I've actually made it.
その一員になれたようで…
I'm not here to play.
遊びに来たんじゃない
I haven't accomplished anything yet.
ワシは
まだ何も成し遂げちゃいない
But still... even if only for a short time...
でも すまん　少しだけ…
Let me soak in this
feeling for a little while.
少しの間だけ
この感情に浸らせとくれ
あっ…　起こしちまったか
すまん
Did I wake you?
Sorry.
I woke up and couldn't get back to sleep.
なんだか目が
冴(さ)えちまってのぅ
I wanted to revisit in my mind
everything I felt today.
忘れんうちに 昨日の感覚の
おさらいをしようと思ってな
You're too excited to sit and rest.
気が高ぶってるんやね
“プロになりたい”
I want to be a pro.
Coming here has only
made that desire greater.
ここに来てその思いは
一層 強くなった
I've been spending time at sumo
stables on my days off lately.
（咲）
最近 休みはこうして―
いろんな相撲部屋
見て回っとるんよ
私の兄が
プロ入り目指しててな
My brother wants to be a pro, too.
I've been checking them out for him.
どの部屋がいいか
兄に代わって 偵察に来てん
（火ノ丸）へえ…
（咲）なあ 潮君
So, Ushio-kun, who was stronger?
ホントは どっちが強いん？
冴ノ山関と久世草介
Saenoyama-zeki or Kuze Sosuke?
It goes without saying that the sekitori
has more power and better technique.
もちろん パワーも
テクニックも―
関取のほうが上じゃし
The sekitori sparred with me
and has been kind to me, but...
関取はワシ相手に
終始 手心を加えとった
なのに ２人が戦えば
どちらが勝つのか―
If they fought each other,
I don't know who would win.
まるで想像がつかん
Maybe Kuze looms too large in my mind.
ワシの中で久世が
大きくなりすぎとるのか…
Their height and techniques
are evenly matched.
久世と冴ノ山関は
上背も取り口も近い
If I'm not able to fight
a full-strength sekitori, I won't...
全力の関取をぶん投げる
くらいじゃねえと―
ワシは きっと…
I understand now.
（柴木山）なるほどな
（火ノ丸）あっ…
So your friend chose Saenoyama
as a stand-in for Kuze Sosuke.
君の友達は 仮想
久世草介として―
冴ノ山を選んだということか
M-Master!
（火ノ丸）お… 親方！
After fighting the sekitori yesterday,
you must have a lot you want to work on.
昨日 関取と戦ったことで―
いろいろと課題も
見えたんじゃないかね？
I'll spar with you.
どれ
いっちょう胸貸してやるか
When I was past my prime,
I got myself a victory
僕が現役時代の晩節に
大和国から もぎ取った金星
by defeating the higher-ranked Yamatokuni.
この経験は
きっと君の役に立つはずだ
I'm sure my experience
will be useful for you.
What's wrong? I don't take
off my shirt for just anyone.
ほら どうした？
僕が胸を出すことなんて
そうそうないぞ
Why would you go this far for me?
（火ノ丸）
どうしてワシなんかに―
こんなに
よくしてくれるんですか
I'd understand if I were a sumo
wrestler destined to turn pro.
プロ入り確実の
有望な選手なら分かります
But I am... well...
でも ワシは その…
I see myself in you. Something us
old folks have a bad habit of doing.
（柴木山）
君に かつての自分を見た
…なんて
年寄りの悪い癖だね
I was called small and helpless,
僕も 小さいだのムリだの
言われ続けて―
but I still fought hard
to become a yokozuna.
それでも本気で
横綱を目指した
I only made it as high as sekiwake.
結果 最高位は関脇
People congratulated me, of course,
but I never achieved my dream.
人は褒めるが僕の
望む所には届かなかったよ
もっと上背があれば…
その思いは冴ノ山に託した
If only I'd been taller...
I passed that dream on to Saenoyama.
だが同時に
もうひとつの思いもあるんだ
But I have one more dream.
To see someone small become a yokozuna.
小さくても
横綱になっていいじゃねえか
見せてくれよ 夢の続きを
Realize that dream for me!
That was a bit long-winded,
but I'm trying to say I like you, kid!
ゴチャゴチャと抜かしたが
要するに気に入ったんだよ！
When you're ready to turn pro, come to me.
プロ入りするときはウチに
来い  いいな？待ってるぞ！
You got that? I'll be waiting.
Yes, sir!
はい！
（力士）何だ？　火ノ丸か？
What? Is Hinomaru up?
あ〜っ！親方が胸貸してる！
俺だって まだなのに！
Hey, the master's practicing with him!
He's never done that for me!
What's this? Everyone's awake now?
なんだ 全員
起きてきちまったのかい？
Aw, screw it! Let's just start practice now!
（寺原）あ〜 くそ
このまま稽古始めっぞ
（力士たち）よ〜し！
All right!
A high schooler's getting the pros excited.
プロが高校生に感化されとる
Ushio Hinomaru-kun, huh?
潮火ノ丸君か…
（咲）お世話になりました！
Thanks for having me!
あ〜 ほんま楽しかった！
Ah, that was so much fun!
Having someone my age
around made things easier.
同い年の潮君が
おったおかげで―
いやすかったってのもあるわ
Thanks.
ありがとう
ウヘヘッ…
それは お互いさまじゃ
Right back at ya.
If both our schools win enough bouts,
we'll see each other at nationals.
お互い勝ち進めば
全国で会えるかもしれんね
Yeah, I'm gonna be at nationals so
I can become the high school yokozuna!
おう　全国行ってワシは
高校横綱になるんじゃ！
And I hope you do.
なれるとええね
But I don't think you'll manage it this
year, because my brother's competing.
ただ今年は私の兄がおるから
難しいとは思うけどな
Your brother?
兄？
You said you were a manager,
but what high school are you from?
咲ちゃん  マネージャーって
言うとったが―
どこの高校なんじゃ？
Tottori Hakuro.
鳥取白楼(とっとりはくろう)
Tottori Hakuro?
鳥取白楼！？　まさか…
You mean...
I'm Tennoji Saki.
Nice to meet you, Ushio Hinomaru-kun.
天王寺(てんのうじ)咲　よろしく
潮火ノ丸君
Tennoji Shido, the national champion!
天王寺獅童(しどう)
全日本選手権王者！
（咲）
千葉の代表は石神高校で
決まりやと思ってたけど―
I thought Ishigami High School was
sure to be the team from Chiba,
but I learned something new today.
思わぬ収穫やで
Onimaru Kunitsuna and
Odachi High School, huh?
鬼丸国綱率いる大太刀高校か
I'll be waiting at the top, Ushio-kun.
頂辺(てっぺん)で待ってるで 潮君
Tennoji, Kuze... and Sada at
Ishigami before I even meet them!
天王寺 久世
その前に まずは石神の沙田(さだ)
I need to perfect my new
technique and beat them all!
新技を完成させ
ワシは あいつらに勝つ！
Shibakiyama Stable
ウヘヘッ！　ほれほれ！
Hey, check it out!
Shibakiyama Stable
What? That's just weird.
ああ？
な… 何だよ？気持ち悪いな
Hey, what do you think?
（火ノ丸）ほれ どうじゃ！
うん？
何だよ？そのだせえシャツは
What's with that lame shirt?
Oh, a Shibakiyama T-shirt!
おお　柴木山部屋
Ｔシャツじゃん！
I'd love one of those!
いいな！
俺も欲しいなぁ
Next Bout   "The Honest Clown"
Captain!
（火ノ丸）部長〜！
（小関）ええっ？